You guys here in there we go you can definitely...out.
As a thank you guys for coming out today has build
...so far pretty good pretty good
has been any other container...
So, how many you guys when...to talk they were kind...the fence about what level of technical
nature we should be and here we kind of landed on a somewhere between a two and three hundred level demo typically
...that means is that we will definitely do some sort of leveling the playing field for folks but,
we won't we won't shy away from code in fact I had quite a bit of interesting stuff to show
you before the before the demo...kicked in this afternoon but, I think we should still have quite a bit
of talk about and we actually might have a little more improv time and we originally scheduled so
just curious how many you guys obviously if you're here you've probably heard of darker how many
folks here are actually running darker in production right now?
Three-and-a-half.
Ok, that's actually about what we see so this is the title talk
...containers using...build something on asher I actually joined microsoft
...offender at microsoft as a full-time...rejoin the team
in the either linux compute team about four or five months ago now and I came back
those super excited about how hungry and what the what the appetite was for going after some of
these bigger open-source and, linux based investments into really,
really super cool see-saw to get up on stage and say microsoft loves linux which, you know,
three or four years ago nobody would...even, you know, start to think about honestly?
So, one of the things I've been working on quite a bit since joining the team is taking a look
at what the container landscape is what some of the things are
out there around containers how people are actually using them what the supporting orchestration tools
are and things like that it's a super interesting space super fast-growing and,
hopefully we'll cover a bunch but today?
So, here's the required...I don't know can you have you guys been able to actually scan the q r codes
...sessions cool...haven't tried one yet.
So, here is the here was the agenda for today session so, it's going to
take about ten maybe twelve ...up-front to talk about just
doctor in the overall container promise that may stretch out a little bit given that some of the
forty minutes on the back...the demo went down this morning but, we saw
...some really cool architectural stuff to talk about and I think it actually will open up the
...for a for a little more interaction between you guys myself.
So, the first part first thing I want to talk today is about darker in
the general container promise around it and we'll start off with this joke
...say for developers around the world developers like yourselves
in myself develops is always been a whale of a problem I think you can probably
...going so,
here's my favorite depiction of dev ops actually in the world and,
you see you see a bunch of starving developers...trying to
...the beast and really having a difficult time with it of course moby dick
butmore popular culture the whale has continued to be a symbol ...dev
ox excellence and that's the fail well so I don't know-how many you guys...on twitter...the fail
...was popular I remember seeing a quite a quite a bunch and
it was really really symbolic actually of you know, company those growing
super quickly really like the idea of moving quickly picking up a bunch of new users but not having
the engineering process kind of in place to catch up with that growth I can't say that anybody would have had
the structure in place to do that because twitter...so-so fasting...but,
this is something that kind of stuck with us so the reality is everyone here knows
that when we get into production no matter how well it worked on my personal boxwe get into
production gm's blow up things go wrong networks go down and things like
...demo machine...boot-up and you know,
it's just part of part of being a developer and what we've gotten used to and
maybe it's because we're, you know, just these type of folks...kind of kind of work through some of
...stuff but it's really okay I mean that's just a reality like there's,
there's failure built into the system you're never going to build a completely
bug free system we joked my startup actually that we spent about ninety percent of
...fixing bugs...the other ten percent of time writing more?
But, those actually one of our or highest efficiency points actually but,
it's okay right so if we if we kind of binary hypothesis that we can in fact
build better systems without sort of...dev ops expertise doctor becomes
...a really interesting thing to talk about so to complete
...metaphor the newest way on the block is this guy
you've all seen and, this time though ...trying to do is really make the
...symbol for good particularly from the perspective of ...the individual developer.
So, over the last two years I've been looking open-source software for a number of years now been involved
in the startups base-two to quite a degree and I don't know if I can ever remember a
startup that's really taken off particular on sort of the core.
Really battle tested infrastructure side of things ...doctor has the last two years
have been ridiculous super successful microsoft has a really public...great relationship
with darkerone of the engineers my team I think was actually the top contributor
...open-source project over the last three or four months and it's a super great product
...at the same time it's really amazing to me
that with something that wasn't,
wasn't really more than and os construct kind of hidden down in the linux
colonel a couple years ago has as turn so many of us in this room and
...enterprises that we talked to and...individual developers and startups we
talk to into doctor believers ...it's...really cool story.
So, when I talk to customers for the first-time we tend to get a lot of folks
who come in and say like...have heard about this buzzword like what stocker
what is containers and we find a lot of time people have a really easy
sort of rocking the top-level benefits of containers right you get the portability story
of community driven steps...not to go reinvent the wheel every time a potential cost savings
...really high scale with sort of been packing better utilization and things they get that part
but the...that we see from people going from individualsort of understanding
...what the dot of what the container benefits are the
...face and making the jump into production is really sort of
wrapping their head around getting out of this traditional vm model ...we kind of just stuff everything
...a single box so the really cool thing about doctor that I always try to land
is a take away is that it helps us build better applications by letting us think
...smaller parts.
The whole way of thinking is basically we treat the application
itself all the components the application as a big single box so at least when I was
...to build applications ...start with the virtual machine?
Some fixed amount of resources some static ip address one box I have something called
an application that was made out of, you know, one or more componentspacket all in their get everything
...work have some sort of a conditions and checking to make sure processes dating go down and
...are being over utilized and, you know, what for the most part is okay?
The problem is that one that system goes down you a have a single
...failure and when your traffic goes up
...services more popular it's it really turns into a very quick curse
...a blessing occurs to have a lot of lot of it attention from
customers so what do we do in that case well traditionally been given,
you know, to high-level options
right we can scale-up which basically means we go out and buy a bigger box and,
still keep sort of the advantages of
packing everything into that known model but still having the disadvantages of having that
...failure or we can scale out and the prevailing the
prevailing opinion from folks I've been talking to at least over the last eighteen months and two-years-old
dockers been coming up is scaling out really appears to be sort of the right way of
doing things or at least the popular opinion for the way to do things right now scaling
up's...lot of times...for very specific applications it's absolutely the way to go if
you can live on one box and you're just doing crazy intense compute staff
super compute kind of stuff and you...seven gazillion...in the box that can be a really,
really viable thing for-you same thing any...coin minors out there?
You can do a for you can you can get a lot of big coin out of a godzilla series on
leisure actually so, there's applications where that makes sense but scaling out is really interesting
the question is like what does it actually meanness scale out and a very naive approach
...the top-level is well I just take the existing model that I have and I
multiply it out across some more resources so in this case you know,
we actually have three times a number of gm's and what I'm calling annexed
...ops complexity addition that
and is different from everybody for me it's about seventeen I would say but I really I really
prefer being in my editor writing code rather than making sure the boxes are staying
...so when you start digging into this sort of first-level strategy for scaling out you know,
it's like well let's start taking a look at what
my application actually needs and instead of looking at is a
single black box it's actually made up of several different containers
...containers might be...the same-size you might have one guy that's, you know,
cpu bound another guides that's io bound and things like that but,
let's just...for the sake the discussion say that we have things that
are different just different functional units right so if I look at the scaling out
...my main my main goal and scaling out was to go and support the api that
...that's getting a ton of infrastructure kind of traffic and kind of a growth?
I actually just sort of not on purpose necessarily scaled out
and put three times a resources and all the extra manpower and complexity of worrying about keeping the other
two web servers up as well one maybe the web server from my
kind of businesses is really cool for just launching my marketing site but,
the api is really where I want to grow and perform so...start looking at a more...level
inside the box just scaling ibm's is not necessarily the right way to go.
So, there's our favorite...again and this is where the doctor guys really made a name for themselves stepping
in so we look at the doctor...process at a high-level
the first kind of thing that we talk about is images and
images is really the you hear a lot of buzz around containers but images are really what
powers containers right they're starting point think of them as,
you know, a class or frozen starting point for you do instantiate containers from.
So, in this case we're saying that we have a sort of a web starting image in api
...image.
And, from that a through the darker
...tools we can actually go take that template for containers and spin up
in arbitrary amount what's really cool about containers is at a you've already
got everything sort of everything you need for that very specific function ready to go and
the image and the boo time is super-fast so if you've ever actually
played with doctor many folks...actually spun up a doctor container and here and kinda gone
...a very nice okay cool I guess that makes sense in this talk?
And, once you've spun up the containers...whole question of okay cool I have these really super
...fast portable a instruments here how do I get them on
to the gm's...the infrastructure that I'm sort of more familiar with and
that's really of sort of the three steps that's really the big open question right now and we're seeing a lot of
really exciting stuff going on generally refer to that sort of the orchestration family
of considerations and that's basically like if I have a workload
that comprise of an arbitrary number of components how do I go and stick it out onto an arbitrary number
boxes and the way it makes no sense for my
application my resources and the financials and things like that.
So, just to sort of finish up...are sort...leveling the playing field
for folks I like to think of containers is lightweight gm's small footprint really fast
boo time they have a shared kernel right which is which is fundamentally different from
a how...traditional virtualization and gm's works where the guessed os
...basically takes over the kernel resources...
From the...
So, containers apps today run anywhere that linux can so I think
all of the five or six officially supported shows of linux on as
...currently run containers today you guys have heard a little bit about the fact
...sure that windows coming out with containers and I think taylor's in here tiller you had your talk
Sweet okay cool well you guys...a lot more about it...but,
very soon in windows so.
We cover this a little bit already I like to think of images being frozen environment's and the things where
we actually create the containers the other cool element that we talk a lot about with
people is sort of the what I call like the and pm phenomenon where you know, no,
jess was this thing that sort of like legitimized this language
that a lot of people thought it died right...was just sort of this
kitty scripting language a lot of the a lot of the successful node was obviously you know,
there's some advantages...and people like some of the asynchronous programming model but a lot of
the actual success can be attributed to just the how the community...shaped up around it and
while...didn't necessarily invent a new operating system
... constructs out like you know,
they invented this idea of containers asia...virtualization what they've
been really successful at doing is providing the right layer of abstraction
for folks like us who don't want to go down and make those direct system calls
interacting with the with the kernel...and gives just enough abstraction away
from that where it's like hey I think this is actually reasonable for me to start playing with the other side of that they've
had just tremendous adoption by the community and folks like you guys so if you ever take a spin around
...there's I don't even know-how many at this point but hundreds maybe thousands of containers up
there...images up there to start your containers from and,
that's really impressive in something one of the reasons why, you know,
we take a look at...relationship with microsoft are so excited to see
to be working with them because we see this really, really dedicated sort-of community support around it.
Last slide...this...the container promise overall
fastportable more resilient apps scale through components
...not just by multiplying the number of lms...have at my disposal.
So, this was the part where we're going to start building something and I'll
give you guys kind of a caveat before that we're not going to be able to get through quite the whole thing but
hopefully we can still stand-up one or two things.
So, how many guys I've ever heard of as your news before?
Nobody so that's because we're going to build it right now and I made up this morning.
So,...we're going to try to do is actually build essentially
the functionality or think about how...be building the functionality of the new page
and acronyms many folks how many folks here familiar this site probably wow,
that's actually a little lower than I thought but for those of you
who don't know this is the this is sort of the startup?
And, open-source haven it's...essentially news blog that's sponsored by
...combinators incubator down here lots of people go up there very simple in
terms of functionality but tons and tons of users and they're actually kind of famous for
having written in some sort of article once even with the amount of traffic the get which is astronomical a
day...are running the whole thing on one server which is really interesting?
So, we're kind of dreaming up like what we might want to do today here's the,
you know, ten seconds spec of sort of attribution what that's going to
look like from a product perspective so as you news is going to be basically like, you know,
the front-page filter of ...news will show the thirty most recent posts
in this case because I'm not going to be able to generate all this post myself
one of the elements we're going to try to bringing here is...api server
dedicated to handling the sm requests from you guys we have a simple mongers db setup which we
also container eyes and the back-end for persisting the stories are posts we had a local
caches stories and that was really the big thing that went down I had I had read is all set up and,
just I cannot figure out some of the
search issues after moving across a couple different environments but hopefully we can work
around some of that stuff and no comments are voting today because we've got
a relatively short amount of time but I will be posting all this stuff and get hub so if
anybody's like really interested in this for some reason I'd be happy to kinda keep banging on a little bit?
here's a first sort of what we would call the sort of a or old-school approach
in the doctor world we do have the option of doing exactly what the folks at
...combinators done right there's,
there's actually a lot of just really practical pragmatic benefits this approach eh
we're familiar with the model
b when everybody's on the same box and you take away a lot of the networking constraints
anddifficulties around coordinating those distributed elements of things you get a lot more
liable experience there's a million prove points out here if you go and look at sort of
like a canonical rails happen all the tutorials you...when you when you type rails into google
...bang you know, you can see something like this right people aren't
thinking about scale out-of-the-box and a lot of those tutorials and you can absolutely get something to work like this?
But, this diagram was drawn in a very specific way such that we could
take a look at the actual functional atomic units of the application
and see how those map back to container in this case what I'm proposing is
we actually break the application out into four separate containers each with its
own functional purpose and each of which we can scale in sort of an atomic
independent fashion of the rest of the application and,
that gives us the advantage of avoiding what we looked
at before where just because I needed to scale one particular element
of my application it doesn't mean I have to go out and...time the resources for everything else?
So, the way that this really simple example kind of looks like from
...standpoint is we have that over here on
the right-hand side we have the sm container sms image whatever and
there that guy is essentially listening to you guys and taking in input all
that guy does is receive the input do a little bit of processing on it make sure that you guys aren't
...going to put us up on...different interesting websites appeared during the show and,
then...it out to the monitored ...db databasefrom there we
have a just a web server that's going to be sort of the server that just gives you the
page in results and also a local cash paired up with that server and,
I opted have the cashier we could very easily just gone with three containers but the...thing is
from an architectural standpoint is kind of interesting when you look at the container
space in general there are schools of thought actually a lot of the
cooper ninety's project you guys are familiar with that might break this up a little differently
and in particular they might argue that you could actually stick the
...cash and the web server in the same image in container and that's because you know,
if you step back a little bit you don't you...you don't go all the way back and see this big black
box you step out a little bit you can see that those are probably pretty tightly coupled
or at least in terms of their benefit to one another they're pretty tightly coupled right, you know,
if I break these out into separate into separate containers only start instantiating I'm sure I can go
out and, scaled the caches independently of the web servers but at some point that has, you know,
very little return...right like if I have eighty-five reddit instances for
...web server there's not a ton of functional utility right there so just
because we can be a purist and, really break amount of these atomic units
...doesn't mean that necessarily it's a hard and fast rules so the...sort-of
...thought around pods I think personally...I interpret that would...a look at this read
cash area as a potential for grouping that that's just a demonstrate the fact that there's,
there's really no, black-and-white
here the big goal is to get yourself into a position where you think you can have
...fail over points multiple scale multiple scaled vectors in a
way of building up the application in a more distributed fashion so with
this high-level architecture essentially get is this type of flexibility so,
just to just...back right basically we can just blow-out any single element
of the application so in this case you say hey you if you need to we had a ton of
records for some reason or start doing some data workloads we want to multiple copies of data we could
...those out...if we needed more sms stuff because you guys...cool we
...and got everybody else calling in which I was I was contemplating a sort of periscope
in this thing and see how many people we could get banging on the server but we'll see if we can actually get
...to boot first and, then you know,
and, then just demonstrating the general scaleability on reticent web in general?
So, the first thing I'm going to take a look at
...hop over to computer here is.
Monitor db.
Samoa.
So, for those of you curious this is actually my officially...microsoft issued
machines so the times are changing in fact.
Thank you, yeah, I like it a lot ...holds like open-source stickers a
lot better so this is my second one that I'm going...can you can see that...all
...of the mce...in the room does anyone know when you're when you're plugged into a eighteen
k display how to get the?
Command plus on terminal.
...I got something...this talk.
Fantastic okay cool so how many you guys actually when you're playing
...how many guys actually are on a linux box?
Parallel forty percent cool anybody's...to darker.
Anybody been successful using which...doctor.
Okay, cool, yeah, I mean boots...for those guys you don't know is actually powered by...
virtual box which is a free virtualization software I actually think it's really handy we actually use
it internally toroll-out the latest bits of our ...plat...I so,
whenever we read the version somebody sticks...new doctor image up on.
The repo so that means you guys can also go...and start banging on...well it's just really,
really convenient for doing really quick, you know, spin-offs and...downs of development
environments what I'm doing here actually is I've gone ahead and,
set up a couple of doctor hosts so all of the machines that...going to be doing
...operations on today are sitting...part of the as part of the relationship with...
we've been trying to come up with...many creative ways we can to help people get into
really solid doctor environment as easily as possible one of those things
You guys use bing just for the picture that a.
Pretty good.
So, if you guys have checked out the new puerto at all and, I know a lot of
you guys if you're if you're doctor fans are probably live more in the command line but,
we do actually have the easiest, easiest way to get started with
...on hatcher is through a marketplace offering...have.
We have two things I'll just spend two seconds on kinda going over so one of them is just
...to server that comes with doctor installed so it's just a pre can
to jakrose come out-of-the-box nothing special we open up, you know,
the reports...reports in an sh to...just reduces, you know,
...or ten minutes of set...time so I tend to go to this one...when I need an
...experimental blocks and...don't have access to my local
booted dockers solution the other thing too is some of the as part of the whole new crt
stacked you guys been hearing about this week...new compute resource providers
and other api is here we also have something called a...extension and,
the dockers extension just like any other extension that we have in asher
is something that through those new templates and to our new api in general you can
...of...it's coming up and,
you just get whatever that small abstracted piece of functionality is for free right so we have you know,...
chef extension if you guys have existing...scripts you just want to stick it in pass it off that diskettes,
you know, seamlessly handled for you guys have a similar sort of thing to get you up and running
on dockers well but,
given that we have given that we already have some boxes...in?
...let's just make sure.
So, how many guys have played with doctor machine?
Couple folks ok so,
...machine is actually part of a three-part wronged approach by
...kind of provide this whole really cool solution for orchestration and
the doctor machines job is to just get you boxes...better,
better doctor host straight they have support for bunch of different clouds local development
...even but, the idea is to just give you sort of that initial topology to start playing around
a doctor the next the next element as swarm what
swarm does is basically axes like a logical load balance or
...in some ways right so if you have five or six different
jakrose sitting behind a or a as part of a swarm the
...client will interact with the entire five or six machines as if it were
a single box so that gives somebody an opportunity to essentially plug-in
...swarm and say okay so what are the rules that make most sense for me in
terms of distributing where those workloads go when I put out-of-the-box and,
the final pieces compose which will takequick look at today but that's a way of saying hey
if my app is made up of several these containers what are the
relationships and dependencies between those guys what sports do I need to open and just give me
...sort of a definitive template that I can put it in super
...and, deploy directly as a single sort
of application thing not just similar to resource groups and that whole concept actually.
So, couple quick commands...for again for folks haven't been around so right now there's there's a
cool trick where the doctor klein if you're on a linux box
you can obviously manage containers that are...box if you're on...box
...which you make you think that your managing containers on your box but that's actually
links box underneath and then ...we like to do allies actually spent
...hosts in the cloud and use these doctor machine environment's to points to
different individual things at a time so right now I'm pointing at th
...one and that is just hanging out and west us on rate let's see
what we've got up I apologize all that's a really good starting point?
So, we were...jumping around a bunch of these things dying off but so,
we take a look at mongers db really quick checks.
So, monetary be is one of the most popular images actually on
doctor hub there's a really cool company
...to...that is interested in a orchestration spaces well if you guys have a chance
that are generally interested in blocker advice checking them out I think they have some really slick
qi for defining applications better that are container based anyway so this is an example of some of the
community stuff they were talking about before looks like this says, you know,
something like ten thousand downloads on it we have a chance to take a look
at different versions and some help stuff it's very similar to...pm but,
when we start working with that actually the first thing that we need to do is
to you get be the base image on the box so they get that we have
a command called what we can actually do...research so for...db?
While that sliding out we can actually do
...pool for the to them among...
And, then...remember that we're not pointing at the remote server.
So, here's...results for all the munging to be options
...there we can get on the box simply by doing...
It's going to download the box and give me a platform essentially...to start off with our debit
...the box I've been playing with...a couple of is the best way to get started with it is with
...run so the doctor run gives you a couple of different options
...high-level give you basically the decision as to whether you want to be a
long-running long-term behind-the-scenes process or something that you're currently interacting with it
is perhaps more short-lived so because
mongers going-to going to stand-up and be a...long-running process for us as a sort of
our main database in this case we you will?
...here so for people
aren't super familiar with dockers command line so we're doing docket run the name is a way to
tag our resources if you leave out the name they'll come up with like a crazy adjective
...a crazy noun and they're really hard to type when you're trying to manage them the default
tag tells us that it's actually going to run as a demon zero-b in a background process where we're not going
to be looking at...output and logs directly and,
then this is probably one of the one of the most interesting things in the
space around containers right now is how you get containers to talk to things that
are outside of containers ...specifically...to containers on the same boxes you so,
one basic primitive the doctor...so the box is the ability to take a
port that's on the container and map it to a port that's on
hosts you essentially open up ports and give yourself endpoints so if I'm trying to
stand-up a web server that's running on...eighty, eighty internally I need to also
expose thatI need to basically pipe that through to the host so I can get traffic in and out.
So, you just like adj.
So, we'll take it off and from scratch to start right that was about like three
seconds even on a shaky kinda internet connection here to actually make
the request efficiently that's how quickly were talking about when we look at really fast
boot and super small footprint so that's a full like
muggy servers spinning up and ready to go right there in two or three seconds
and for those folks that have done the process of installing it yourself under local
box and you linux a or sex it's certainly not that quick and,
the big take away there is a...in the big scheme of things there's not going to be three-second set kind
of make-up make-or-break deployment necessarily but it's just a testament
...of the flexibility if you have to spend multiple hours getting a database setup when you could
get a container spun up with similar-type of...go kick the tires on it that's
actually really cool in terms of getting people the to get started on trying new technologies and,
I think it's a really a really great...darker so we kicked off the darker
the muggy container so we can check out what's running currently on the box by doing
doctor ps so it's just, you know, essentially the processes that are being managed by
doctor you can see that it pulled from the latest
...that we had for ...db from to them it's been
...for about a minuteone of the things that you can specify when you're building a
...image is the command gets run...container actually starts
...so I can be any sort of arbitrary script can be any executable
it's already on the boxer...you add installed...part of as part of the image so,
it gives you the flexibility basically...to do whatever you want there I'm not sure I've
never tried to do this before but doctor has a
function called doctor exec which allows us to basically jump inside
a running container even if they're running as a demon in the background so I can be really helpful when you're
trying to...figure out what's wrong because the things not sort of front-and-center when it's a displaying a
Nl db an been bash.
And, now I'm sitting in...muggy container so,
I can go...in picket logs or whatever, whatever like to do their so that's a really
cool thing where even if you've got a bunch of these container spitting out there never really like
...it's not like you kick it off and you can't get back into them which is sort of
a misconception we...a lot when people are starting with it so anyway right now we've got ...db
instance up into prove that that's...for you guys we have so, that we opened up to different
ports I think twenty-seven seventeen and twenty seventeen?
So, this is the default beautiful management...ships of muggy these days
you will see at this point because...actually have no databases
...sort of the standard admin account holders just a clean box that is fresh from
boot got that up and that's the first part of the application
samoa?
So, the second...second part of the application is actually getting a
little more into the details around what it takes to create your own image so.
Among these case we started, you know, somebody down the hard work for us right they took some stripped down version of
a...to or whatever the base images that all the configuration got into a really nice like secure
...configuration and we were just able to go to go leverage as a as sort of
an open-source offering when you want to
...getting into more complex deployments though it becomes really important that you field
you get comfortable with building your own images that you can start containers from the way the
...exposed to do that is to something called the doctor file at a very-high-level
doctor files are basically just a really restricted set of
commands that you can think of as applying layers and operations on
to images start with so when you guys hear things like core os and
...snappy and things like that those guys are trying to be like the most
basic image they can be it's like the most stripped down version of linux...reasonably
safe in performant and, things like that and basically what they're trying to do is give
use close to a blank canvas as you can get for applying your own custom things on
today image that's really cool if folks that are out there who are going to
fans I've been using...for years was not a huge fan of the fact that you know,
as...became more modern right we started having things like ad...and stuff like that shipping
...there when you're looking at doing things like fast
dev ops deployments inconsistent environment's...to start from scratch as much as you possibly can?
So, ...a look at how that works.
You guys know the command for e-max as I can do the same thing format.
...have you guys not even...dessert.
from what you can see actually I'll do a just a really quick navigation through it we always start with
a from statement when you're...image so that's typically taking a really a really basic thing or
maybe a really basic thing plus one-quarter core piece of your of your infrastructure
...looking to do so in this case
...looking to stand-up basic express node web server so I just started from the
base node image that's most popular...had right so it's a
...two-plus the...installation of node and that's it from their doctor provide some really
basic operations that you can do have this ad functionality copy
functionality you can change working directories you can copy things and you can run arbitrary
scripts and then at the end once you've got everything kind of set...see here that I
...my package json define the...server and,
then run and pm install to get all the dependencies in there and then the last thing you do is you have
an option of doing a...the entry point or...c and d which allows you to run
in arbitrary script when it's up there you can always override that bypassing in some sort of
command on the command line when you're starting up the container but,
by defaults like I know this is my web server got
...configured exactly the way I want to all the files in there so I just want
...to startup exactly the same way every time without me having to do anything else in this case you're just you're just
...up the server so based on that file we can do is what's called the
doctor build so I'm in the container right...the directory
right now and to do a doctor build it's just doctor build?
We have dash t for tag so in this case...just call web and,
the doctor file is sitting right here in this in this directory so...that off.
So, basically what it's doing decker tries to be really because people almost never get
their doctor images right the first-time I think I've
rebuilt this probably ten or twenty times they try to be really smart in terms of making life efficient for
you guys so a they do a bunch of caching when they bring down images if...have the basic
going-to image on the box...do that very smart about doing sort of iterative file
and layering on top of on top of the image to get a built as quickly as possible but in general, you know,
for this kind of thing I'm copying over some files I'm doing it remotely some kind of sending up a build context
into the cloud it might take a couple minutes but certainly extremely,
extremely quick relative to
a full powered full-size bhd for instance.
The last thing that we're going to show today was the was docket compose and
docking impose was we're talking about before where
it's sort of the third piece of dockers overall orchestration strategy and it lets you create a
jpm file which is sort of you know,
a nice man's json I guess and, define your application...the dependencies
...relationships between containers in your applicationand, let-you deployed
very similarly to how we've been talking about resource groups this week with asher so,
this is where in the process today the structured
...for me?
We take a look at what.
We have here so,
I've created another sort of working folder for my sms server
took a similar approach the de actually if we look at the doctor...really quickly
it's very similar to towards the first server that I made couple different file differences and,
couple things I want to do in terms of configuration but very straightforward it's really easy to work with
a doctor files and get...super repeatable thing to work with and, then if we kick this
...we share the...
So, right into the context again.
Another good reason for actually passing in the name variables of containers
because it's a lot easier to work with three-letter names you can remember my opinion at least.
...that's well, it's...here you take a look at what is a new feature
in here that we haven't talked about before which is this link thing and a link this a
magic stuff similar to the way like rails behind-the-scenes
will light up a lot of cool stuff for you if you just kind of follow the rules
...does link does the same thing for doctor containers particular on the same on the same
host so if you define a link...server and data workload or database
something like that basically have a really shorthand way of communicating with each other
...code so in this case we are giving we are linking the
sm server with the databases got a right to so instead of me having to have like an
ip address hard coded in the thing I can just refer to the name
of the database and be able to have a have a connection shrink...essentially.
So, this is kicking off and while this is kicking off the since we had
an error on the caching the front-end here this is our new this is going to be our new hacker news right
here it's command line news apparently and,
if everything is working right now what's happening
behind-the-scenes we actually have to doctor hosts we have one container
...running the sm server which is sitting there waiting for you guys...it and,
we have one server that as one...running
...muggy workload those guys are linked with the short so they don't even have to know about where each other
our that ought to do any sort of discovery they can just reference each other directly
view link and when the...new sms messages...to dump it in
...database and,...dismissing sort of...display there but I believe if
someone wants to do a little data for me here we can?
...text to.
This number and,
just be careful because my messaging rates to apply in this case this is a thing on...I set up
as if anybody's ever toilet before it's fantastic somebody sends.
...going from milwaukee what hoosier from las vegas.
Are very nice...here instead of las vegas?
...take it back over to guys can see these coming in so, this is a...
to containers sort of workload...production and real-time you guys are sending us text
or parsing that getting it sticking at back-up and among go db dot database
...up there really super solid what's cool about it is that I don't have to take the whole
system offline right so if I wanted to make a change to the output that was going to be made on
me ...receiving the...right here I can leave the database container
...independently is multiple containers I can take down one of the sm servers
and update that while you get sort of this upgraded fail over zone functionality and,
they're able to
work and scale independently of each other in that case so I apologize for
not getting the point where we had the really cool like hacker news clone up there but you guys can at least see that the
data is being pipe through container backs and, it's actually really,
really simple the setup leveraging some of the some of the contract stocker gives you.
Also thanks for participating that's awesome.
So, to kind of wrap-up...back side of this here.
So, dockers really, really cool at least in my opinion I get to work on all the time
on a team that contributes directly to dockers I think the...guys here and
in the room at least upstairs and they've got some cool stickers and swagger you guys
too but if you actually take a look at the people in the space right now there's some really,
really interesting players in the space doctor obviously is
...at the front-and-center those guys but one of the people we one of the folks that we
announce relationship with yesterday actually what are the...sphere guys and
...sphere is a super cool company that's taking a look at well if I have a
bunch of its like thousands of nodes thousand hundreds and thousands of computers nodes
how do I make sense of deploy my workloads on of those and I should be able to tree all of those things
is a single compute resources similar to the way that swarms approaching sort of the swarming
compose scenario I should be able to
put really cool constraints and not have to worry about the develop side of things I should get the monitoring and the ability
to spin those things...against a predefine definition that I have expert my expected
aso a naptime cluster hq is also is really cool and you guys should check them out if
you've been thinking at all about working a...production so we're currently
...certain work with them to help bring ...storage drive around to algeria's well but these guys are
doing some really cool stuff in solving one of the really hard problems of containers
...which is handling stateful workloads and data you can't afford to lose
so containers just by their natural characteristics fantastic for things like burst
a workloads and things like that if you don't care about the data and you can lose a couple of things
the ability to spin up a gazillion of them super quickly is really attractive but as soon as you have
business critical information and databases and things that need to stay in particular
regions and things like that without a proper orchestration
story and mechanisms for maintaining that security instability and, resilience
...really you it's really hard to convince some people to go...production with containers cluster
each q as a product called blocker that's really in the early beta stages but is really,
really cool and promising so I go recommend checking them out as well if you if you're interested in that
isn't this really cool feature where I can actually move my database containers around and
within the database network that it knows about it will essentially...sort of like
a dns proxy for-you and handle all the routing...have to do self discovery you can move
boxes safely seamlessly up scale-up and things like that ...it's really neat?
In containers are really just the start were as a company as a developer myself really
excited to see where the container spaces going I'm seeing more every event we speak
...seeing more and more people that actually made the jump from sort of the standard bm approach
to actually going after containers trying to put in production working with more and more startups
...are running like beta versions of things I core os...versions of things like
core os...to take advancetake advantage of really the bleeding edge
...features the dockers offering so wrap-up really quickly.
I will be posting once we get this working the code for
the full hacker news clone up on this site you guys are interested in, you know,
just like how you interact with audio which is what powered some of the smm stuff there
...you can check out if you've never really played with
doctor files before or even some of the basic features around doctor compose
in defining those relationships and links...all be up there so?
Here's an obligatory slide please check out any this any of this training if
...it's interesting you guys and...that I think we've got like four or
five minutes left for open questions what for you guys to keep texan
...actually anybody still taxing?
...a pretty cool sample authored upon instagram later.